# John Foderaro **Software Engineer**

#### johnfoderaro@icloud.com

Tinton Falls, NJ | https://ifod.me

# Summarv

Software Engineer specializing in full stack web development and the Node.js ecosystem. Strong understanding of asynchronous programming for both the server and the client. Extensive experience in developing web applications and software, internal tools and utilities, and APIs. Fan of and contributor to open source software. Explorer of new ideas and concepts in the world of programming and software engineering.

#### **Recent Projects**

#### GitHub Web Hook (OSS)

Node is application to facilitate server-side actions based upon user activities on a GitHub repository

# Mark Down Editor (OSS)

Node is application with MongoDB and React front-end for creating content in the Markdown format with YAML

#### Sales Assistant (WorkWave)

Node.js application with React front-end that allows customers to schedule and purchase services online

#### Static Site Generator (WorkWave)

Node is application that enables the creation of a static site projects for WorkWave's marketing team

#### Static Site Deploy Pipeline (WorkWave)

Node is application for continuous deploys of static site projects for WorkWave's marketing team

### **Employment**

WorkWave **Software Engineer**  Holmdel, NJ

March 2018 - Present

Full stack software engineer for WorkWave's PestPac SaaS product:

- Develops and deploys new features to a base of about 11,000 users
- Works within the new features team along side fellow engineers, QA/QE, UI/UX, and product members
- Tech stack includes MS SQL, Node.js, .NET, VB6, Classic ASP back-end with jQuery and React front-end
- Lead the development of the PestPac Sales Assistant React application, released December 2018

Web Developer July 2014 - March 2018

Full stack web developer with an emphasis on front-end JavaScript for WorkWave's marketing department

- Developed responsive UI layouts, new pages and features, and new navigation and CTA components
- Worked with various APIs and services to integrate marketing data, such as Marketo and Salesforce
- Championed the transition to static site generators and a new developer workflow to benefit the lead generation efforts, reducing development time of new website features by approximately 50%
- Mentored Junior Web Developer in modern JavaScript (ES6+) and web development best practices

**NBC** Universal

New York, NY

SEO Specialist March 2013 - July 2014 Designed and executed campaigns for NBCNews.com, msnbc.com, TODAY.com and iVillage.com:

- Increased iVillage.com organic traffic by approximately 15% over the course of Q2 and Q3 of 2013
- Mitigated the SEO risk of NBCNews.com 2014 site relaunch which resulted in ~1 million 404 Not Found errors
- Worked with editorial staff and engineers to ensure technical CMS code changes ensured SEO success

WorkWave (Formerly Marathon Data Systems)

Wall, NJ

# **Web Designer**

October 2010 - March 2013

Web designer and marketing specialist for the external marketing agency:

Built client websites using the Joomla CMS with a strong focus in front-end HTML, CSS, JavaScript

#### Education

Monmouth University

**Bachelor of Arts** 

Major in History and Minor in Geography

West Long Branch, NJ

January 2010